<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-15T12:29:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Alina Avanesyan</title><subtitle>Alina's personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">MAES grant proposal on using a NGS-approach for meta-barcoding the lanternfly gut contents has been funded!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/MAES-grant-funded/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MAES grant proposal on using a NGS-approach for meta-barcoding the lanternfly gut contents has been funded!" /><published>2020-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/MAES-grant-funded</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/MAES-grant-funded/">&lt;p&gt;I was very pleased to know that our grant proposal entitled “Identification of host plant use by the invasive spotted lanternfly (Lycorma delicatula) using next-gen DNA sequencing technology” has been funded by Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station Competitive Grant Program! &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this one-year study, we have proposed using a next-generation sequencing technology (‘Amplicon-EZ’) for meta-barcoding plant species from the gut contents of the invasive spotted lanternfly, Lycorma delicatula. Our current findings of plant DNA detection from the gut contents of the lanternfly nymphs using Sanger sequencing (Avanesyan and Lamp, manuscript is in preparation) suggest that while the observed lanternfly nymphs actively move on a host plant they may not utilize it for feeding. A substantial number of the nymphs (~90%) we have analyzed showed the ingested DNA from a host plant other than the plant from which the nymphs were collected. However, Sanger sequncing allowed us to detect and identify only DNA from one unique ingested plant. Conducting meta-barcoding of the lanternfly gut contents will allow us to detect multiple plant DNA fragments and detangle all possible associations with the host plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/plan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Overview of the proposed activities for the project
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/ngs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;BLAST results of the gut content of the 3rd nymphal instar collected from a maple tree 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To date, we have successfully sequenced the gut content from one lanternfly nymph which yielded 139 ingested plant sequences. Among these fragments 12% were readable (i.e. long enough to use the BLAST engine in GenBank and identify the species), and among the readable ones - 12% were from the Bartramiaceae family, and 88% were from the Lamiaceae family. A substantial number of these plants are non-woody species which is very interesting (and important!) as the spotted lanternfly is considered to be a predominant tree pest. Looking forward to our work on this grant and more sequencing!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was very pleased to know that our grant proposal entitled “Identification of host plant use by the invasive spotted lanternfly (Lycorma delicatula) using next-gen DNA sequencing technology” has been funded by Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station Competitive Grant Program!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lanternfly paper published in PLOS ONE!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/SLF-paper-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lanternfly paper published in PLOS ONE!" /><published>2019-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/SLF-paper-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/12/SLF-paper-published/">&lt;p&gt;One year of work, four months in review, two months in revision, and here you go - a wonderful Christmas present from &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0226995&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/a&gt;! This paper summarizes the results of my morphological work on the spotted lanternfly, an aggressive invasive insect in the eastern US. In part, thanks to intensive training in scanning electron microscopy at the Laboratory for Biological Ultrastructure. &lt;!--more--&gt; In this study, I was able to investigate the external structures of the lanternfly mouthparts and tarsal parts, as well as a number of sensilla, which play an important role in the lanternfly primary contact with the surface of a host plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is our &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2019_SLFmorphology.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avanesyan, A.&lt;/strong&gt;, Maugel T.K., and W. Lamp (2019) External morphology and developmental changes of tarsal tips and mouthparts of the invasive spotted lanternfly, Lycorma delicatula. PLOS ONE, &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0226995&quot;&gt;doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0226995&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few selected figures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/slf-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Morphometric characteristics measured for the labium, the stylet fascicle and the tarsal tip of Lycorma delicatula.(A) Labium and stylets. (B) Tarsal tip, the dorsal view. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0226995.g001
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/slf-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;SEM of the mandibular stylets of Lycorma delicatula at each developmental stage. (A) First instar nymph. (B) Second instar nymph. (C) Third instar nymph. (D) Fourth instar nymph. (E) Adult female. (F) Adult male. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0226995.g010
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/slf-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;SEM of the tarsal tips of the forelegs of Lycorma delicatula at each developmental stage. (A) First instar nymph. (B) Second instar nymph. (C) Third instar nymph. (D) Fourth instar nymph. (E) Adult female. (F) Adult male. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0226995.g012
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/slf-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;SEM of the labial tip of Lycorma delicatula (Third instar nymph). (A) Sensory fields. DSF, dorsal sensory field; VSF, ventral sensory field. (B) and (D) Dorsal sensory field. CS, clavate sensilla; FS, forticate sensilla, FLS, finger-like sensilla; CP, cuticular process; PGSM, multiporous peg sensilla; PGS, peg sensilla; P, pore. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0226995.g008
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been challenging and very interesting work. In this study, we focused on assessing changes in morphology of (a) the lanternfly mouthparts (stylets and labium), and (b) the lanternfly tarsal tips (arolia and tarsal claws) at each developmental stage. Our study revealed several interesting developmental patterns which potentially allow L. delicatula to better attach to a host plant and deeper penetrate to the host plant tissues at the late nymphal stages and adult stage. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The labium in adults consists of five segments whereas the nymphs have four labial segments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The labium and stylet length, as well as the tarsal claw dispersal from the arolium, exponentially increase by 4th- instar nymph and adult stage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mandibular stylets possess four indentations on the outer surface of the stylet apical part which become more evident in 4th-instar nymphs and adult&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Longitudinal striations between indentations are present on mandibular stylets of 4th-instar nymphs and adults&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arolia surface becomes wrinkled in late instars and adults&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes in the angle of arolium growth follow the quadratic growth curve; the angle becomes obtuse in adults which potentially causes increase of the arolia basal width&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additionally, we have found six morphological types of sensilla which are present at the labial tip at each developmental stage of L. delicatula; which potentially indicates the lanternfly ability to effectively explore the host plant suitability at each developmental stage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first study on variation in the lanternfly external morphology across various developmental stages, and our findings are critical for investigating and predicting the lanternfly host range, and the lanternfly dispersal to new host trees at each developmental stage.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One year of work, four months in review, two months in revision, and here you go - a wonderful Christmas present from PLOS ONE! This paper summarizes the results of my morphological work on the spotted lanternfly, an aggressive invasive insect in the eastern US. In part, thanks to intensive training in scanning electron microscopy at the Laboratory for Biological Ultrastructure.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bryan continues studying Molecular Biology at the University of Maryland!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/bryan-school-news/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bryan continues studying Molecular Biology at the University of Maryland!" /><published>2019-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/bryan-school-news</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/bryan-school-news/">&lt;p&gt;I was very pleased to learn that my former mentee, Bryan, a high school student, was admitted to the University of Maryland where he continues studying Molecular Biology. Bryan was working with us during last Spring semester, and I was really impressed by his incredible progress during those several months. &lt;!--more--&gt;  Bryan joined us in January knowing nothing about wet lab techinques for DNA barcoding process; he worked once a week only learning all the steps; and by the end of April he had successfully extracted genomic DNA from 100+ leafhopper samples, amplified plant DNA from leafhopper guts and succesfully obtained and deposited four plant sequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the first author on four GenBank submissions which were approved and are currently available in the NCBI GenBank database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stancliff, B., Avanesyan, A. and W. Lamp. (2019) Vicia faba var. major tRNA-Leu (trnL) gene, partial sequence; chloroplast. Direct Submission, GenBank Accession no. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/nuccore/MK934667.1&quot;&gt;MK934667&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stancliff, B., Smith, D., Avanesyan, A. and W. Lamp. (2019) Pisum sativum tRNA-Leu (trnL) gene, partial sequence; chloroplast. Direct Submission, GenBank Accession no. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/nuccore/MK919208.1&quot;&gt;MK919208&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stancliff, B., Abdelwahab, O., Avanesyan, A. and W. Lamp. (2019) Vigna unguiculata tRNA- Leu (trnL) gene, partial sequence; chloroplast. Direct Submission, GenBank Accession no. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/nuccore/MK883492.1&quot;&gt;MK883492&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stancliff, B., Ho, J., Avanesyan, A. and W. Lamp. (2019) Helianthus annuus tRNA-Leu (trnL) gene, partial sequence; chloroplast. Direct Submission, GenBank Accession no. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/nuccore/MK875279.1&quot;&gt;MK875279&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His work was the essential part of our paper on the use of molecular markers for plant DNA detection from leafhopper gut contents (the manuscript is currently submitted).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bryan was also featured in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/johncarrollschool/photos/a.549607655156223/2147147948735511/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot;&gt;The John Carroll School News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so happy for him!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was very pleased to learn that my former mentee, Bryan, a high school student, was admitted to the University of Maryland where he continues studying Molecular Biology. Bryan was working with us during last Spring semester, and I was really impressed by his incredible progress during those several months.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guest Editor for Insects, special issue on molecular gut content analysis!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/guest-editor-insects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guest Editor for Insects, special issue on molecular gut content analysis!" /><published>2019-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/guest-editor-insects</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/guest-editor-insects/">&lt;p&gt;I’m serving as a Guest Editor for journal Insects, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mdpi.com/journal/insects/special_issues/gut_trophic_interact&quot;&gt;Special Issue “Molecular Gut Content Analysis: Deciphering Trophic Interactions of Insects”&lt;/a&gt;. I’m co-editing this special issue with Dr. Bill Lamp. Our proposal for this special issue has been approved, and the special issue has just been announced  &lt;!--more--&gt; on the journal’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Special Issue welcomes recent research on plant and animal DNA detection in the gut contents of insect herbivores and predators, respectively, as well as insect DNA detection in the gut contents of their predators, vertebrate or invertebrate. DNA-based protocols, short experimental reports, and original research articles, as well as review papers that broadly cover issues relating to molecular gut content analysis of various insect species (leaf-chewing insects, sap-feeders, soil-dwelling insects, etc.) and insect predators (both invertebrates and vertebrates) are of interest for this Special Issue. Studies that utilize both basic and advanced molecular biology methods are invited for submission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deadline for the submission is March 15, 2020. I’m planning to contribute to this special issue with some results of my DNA barcoding work, and I’m looking forward to receiving new submissions!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m serving as a Guest Editor for journal Insects, Special Issue “Molecular Gut Content Analysis: Deciphering Trophic Interactions of Insects”. I’m co-editing this special issue with Dr. Bill Lamp. Our proposal for this special issue has been approved, and the special issue has just been announced</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Presented at the 2nd UMD Postdoctoral Research Symposium</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/umd-postdoc-symposium/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presented at the 2nd UMD Postdoctoral Research Symposium" /><published>2019-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/umd-postdoc-symposium</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/umd-postdoc-symposium/">&lt;p&gt;Last Friday, I had a poster presentation at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://gradschool.umd.edu/postdocs/career-and-professional-development/postdoctoral-research-symposium-2019&quot;&gt;2nd UMD Postdoctoral Research Symposium&lt;/a&gt;. I presented ‘the morphological part’ of my lanternfly research – &lt;!--more--&gt;the adaptations of the lanternfly mouthparts and tarsal tips to their host plant usage. I enjoyed both the symposium and the opportunity to present my research. This is the 2nd postdoctoral symposium at the University of Maryland, and I really liked its workshops and the opportunity to meet and talk to other postdoctoral researchers across the university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2019_EBESA_poster.pdf&quot;&gt;poster&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/postdoc_symp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;My poster at the 2nd UMD Postdoctoral Research Symposium. (September 13, 2019; College Park, MD)
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last Friday, I had a poster presentation at our 2nd UMD Postdoctoral Research Symposium. I presented ‘the morphological part’ of my lanternfly research –</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Successful amplification of COI partial gene from dragonfly prey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/prey-identification/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Successful amplification of COI partial gene from dragonfly prey" /><published>2019-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/prey-identification</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/prey-identification/">&lt;p&gt;Molecular identification of prey in predator diet - this is a new challenge in my DNA barcoding work; I amplify DNA from dragonfly prey items (a new lab project I’m involved in).  &lt;!--more--&gt;In addition to a gut content analysis, I’m working with degraded DNA from dragonfly feces. Last week I successfully amplified and sequenced COI partial gene from dragonfly feces produced during the first 2 hours post ingestion. The sequence analysis with subsequent BLAST results showed that the prey item was a crane fly. Surprisingly enough the DNA from the crane fly wasn’t degraded and an isolated fragment of 667 bp showed good sequence quality. These exciting results can make identification of dragonfly prey possible and accurately confirm (or even poitn to new) trophic interactions in dragonfly natural habitats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/odonata.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Obtaining the DNA of a crane fly from dragonfly feces.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Molecular identification of prey in predator diet - this is a new challenge in my DNA barcoding work; I amplify DNA from dragonfly prey items (a new lab project I’m involved in).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guest lecture on invasive species tomorrow!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/05/guest-lecture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guest lecture on invasive species tomorrow!" /><published>2019-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/05/guest-lecture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/05/guest-lecture/">&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited about my upcoming guest lecture tomorrow. This lecture is on invasive species for an undegraduate honors class on insect biodiversity.  &lt;!--more--&gt;I gave the similar lecture last year but this year I have considerably modified the lecture content and class activities, I hope the students will enjoy it. I am also looking forward to sharing my latest results from my lanternfly project and showing the preserved samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/guest-lecture-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;lecture&lt;/a&gt;, and here is the &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/misc/guest-lecture-worksheet-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;worksheet&lt;/a&gt; for the students to follow our class activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/lecture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m very excited about my upcoming guest lecture tomorrow. This lecture is on invasive species for an undegraduate honors class on insect biodiversity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maryland Day in pictures - 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/maryland-day-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maryland Day in pictures - 2" /><published>2019-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/maryland-day-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/maryland-day-2/">&lt;p&gt;We had a great time on campus enjoying yet another &lt;a href=&quot;https://marylandday.umd.edu/&quot;&gt;Maryland Day&lt;/a&gt;! While I was busy in our “Discover a Swamp” room, the rest of my family enjoyed ice-cream, baloons, trucks, books, and of course, our bugs! &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/md-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We had a great time on campus enjoying yet another Maryland Day! While I was busy in our “Discover a Swamp” room, the rest of my family enjoyed ice-cream, baloons, trucks, books, and of course, our bugs!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nina succesfully presented at her school research symposium</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/school-symposium/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nina succesfully presented at her school research symposium" /><published>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/school-symposium</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/school-symposium/">&lt;p&gt;Last Friday, I enjoyed attending &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greenbeltnewsreview.com/news-stories/erhs-symposium-shows-off-students-science-acumen/&quot;&gt;Eleanor Roosevelt High School Annual Research Symposium&lt;/a&gt;. Nina, one of my mentees, presented final results of her DNA barcoding work. &lt;!--more--&gt;  This was her year-long project on identification of wetland and stream species of isopods using DNA barcoding. The overall idea of the project was to show whether wetland and stream communities demonstrate biological connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nina presented a poster showing all the steps of the DNA barcoding process she learned during her year-long internship, as well as our current results. Using phylogenetic reconstructions, Nina has pinpointed three unique stream species and two unique wetland species which do not overlap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/nina001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Nina presented her final poster at the ERHS Research Symposium (April 26, 2019; Greenbelt, MD) 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last Friday, I enjoyed attending Eleanor Roosevelt High School Annual Research Symposium. Nina, one of my mentees, presented final results of her DNA barcoding work.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Teaching summer course in Evolutionary Biology</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/summer-teaching/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Teaching summer course in Evolutionary Biology" /><published>2019-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/summer-teaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/summer-teaching/">&lt;p&gt;I am super excited to teach a graduate course in &lt;a href=&quot;https://oes.umd.edu/graduates-post-baccalaureates-professionals/professional-graduate-programs/master-chemical-life-sciences-mclfs/advising-plan-study-mclfs#CLFS609J&quot;&gt;Evolutionary Biology&lt;/a&gt; this summer as an instructor of record. This is a fully online course offered through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://oes.umd.edu/graduates-post-baccalaureates-professionals/professional-graduate-programs/master-chemical-life-sciences-mclfs?utm_medium=display&amp;amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;amp;utm_campaign=oes_mclfs&amp;amp;utm_content=mclfs_display&amp;amp;utm_medium=paid_search&amp;amp;utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_campaign=oes_mclfs&amp;amp;utm_content=mclfs_search&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw19DlBRCSARIsAOnfRehbFayBrGjDxdjTOXcbbEoUtB_YH1qfzXTbt15jorhoZ_3kD8vGa_waAq7AEALw_wcB&quot;&gt;Master of Chemical and Life Sciences program&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!--more--&gt; (a content-based, professional master’s degree for middle and high school teachers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guidetoonlineschools.com/degrees/masters-biology&quot;&gt;ranked #6&lt;/a&gt; in the nation as best online master’s in biology programs). This is going to be a very interesting experience for me: I taught Evolutionary Biology as part of other courses before, but I have never taught it as a separate course. Also, this is my first time teaching online, and I am sure I will learn a lot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course has been offered for several years, so it has all the course materials set up. It includes various interactive assignments and discussions, as well as a final project which is a real lesson the teachers will demonstrate and will ‘take’ with them to their class. I really like this final part and that the teachers can create something new based on what they have learned, and they can apply it right away in their daily work. I am very much looking forward to teaching this summer course and meeting my new students!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am super excited to teach a graduate course in Evolutionary Biology this summer as an instructor of record. This is a fully online course offered through the Master of Chemical and Life Sciences program</summary></entry></feed>