<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-16T15:56:35-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Alina Avanesyan</title><subtitle>Alina's personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Presented at the EB-ESA-2021 meeting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/eb-esa-meeting2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presented at the EB-ESA-2021 meeting" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/eb-esa-meeting2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/eb-esa-meeting2021/">&lt;p&gt;This week I presented my research on interspecific and intraspecific interactions of Anastatus reduvii at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://esa.confex.com/esa/2021eb/meetingapp.cgi/Paper/153355&quot;&gt;Eastern Branch meeting of the Entomological Society of America&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;!--more--&gt;In my presentation, I focused on whether (and how) the behavior of A. reduvii changes in the presence of another A. reduvii individual, as well as in the presence of Trissolcus japonicus (a natural enemy of BMSB in Asia).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, using a combination of behavioral trials with A. reduvii on the BMSB egg masses, we recorded and analyzed 13 various types of behavior A. reduvii performed. Our results demonstrated that (a) A. reduvii performed up to four new types of behavior in the presence of other parasitoids; (b) A. reduvii spent significantly less time off the egg mass and more time walking in the presence of another A. reduvii and T. japonicus; (c) A. reduvii spent more time probing/ovipositing on the egg mass in the presence of another A. reduvii than that in the presence of T. japonicus, and (d) in the presence of another A. reduvii, both host-feeding and probing/ovipositing showed significant association with eggs outcome, resulting in ~50% reduction of BMSB hatchlings. We believe that our findings would allow us to better understand interspecific and intraspecific interactions of A. reduvii and, their effect on the BMSB egg fate, which is valuable for developing effective biological control of BMSB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2021_EBESA_talk.pdf&quot;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/EB_ESA_2021.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week I presented my research on interspecific and intraspecific interactions of Anastatus reduvii at the Eastern Branch meeting of the Entomological Society of America.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Will serve on the University Senate!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/ptk-senator/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Will serve on the University Senate!" /><published>2021-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/ptk-senator</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/ptk-senator/">&lt;p&gt;I’m very grateful and I feel deeply honored to be elected as a PTK senator, to represent the needs, interests, and views of professional track faculty on the University Senate. &lt;!--more--&gt; This is my first experience with this, and I’m really looking forward to serving on the Senate and continuing to contribute to the academic life of our university as much as I can.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m very grateful and I feel deeply honored to be elected as a PTK senator, to represent the needs, interests, and views of professional track faculty on the University Senate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reviewer Board Member for Agriculture!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/reviewer-board-agriculture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reviewer Board Member for Agriculture!" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/reviewer-board-agriculture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/reviewer-board-agriculture/">&lt;p&gt;I was invited to serve on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mdpi.com/journal/agriculture/submission_reviewers&quot;&gt;Reviewer Board Member&lt;/a&gt; for Agriculture. I really enjoy serving as a reviewer and find it very rewarding. &lt;!--more--&gt; As an author, I got to appreciate the time the editors and reviewers dedicate and effort they make during the peer-review process, as well as the challenges along the way. Being an reviewer means for me not only “returning” the time and efforts to the other reviewers, but it is also a non-stop learning process through which I improve my research and share what I learn with other researchers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was invited to serve on Reviewer Board Member for Agriculture. I really enjoy serving as a reviewer and find it very rewarding.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our paper on potato leafhopper feeding published!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/PLH-paper-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our paper on potato leafhopper feeding published!" /><published>2020-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/PLH-paper-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/PLH-paper-published/">&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to share that our paper entitled “Detecting Ingested Host Plant DNA in Potato Leafhopper (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae): Potential Use of Molecular Markers for Gut Content Analysis” is published in Journal of Economic Entomology.  &lt;!--more--&gt; In this study we focused on optimizing a DNA-based method for host plant identification of E. fabae and investigating the longevity of the ingested plant DNA as one of the potential applications of the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is our &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2021_PLH_feeding.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Update:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/26/2021: The paper has just been assigned to &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jee/article-abstract/114/1/472/5955538?redirectedFrom=fulltext&quot;&gt;February issue of JEE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m happy to share that our paper entitled “Detecting Ingested Host Plant DNA in Potato Leafhopper (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae): Potential Use of Molecular Markers for Gut Content Analysis” is published in Journal of Economic Entomology.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Field season is done</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/10/field-season-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Field season is done" /><published>2020-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/10/field-season-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/10/field-season-2020/">&lt;p&gt;Field season 2020 is done, and I’m looking forward to analyzing the data, parasitoid identifications, and preparing to the next summer. &lt;!--more--&gt; I really enjoy my new projects, because everything is so interesting :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/stickycards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Sticky cards for monitoring BMSB parasitoids (Aug, 2020; MD) 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/g.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/al.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;My little helper at the apple orchard :) 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/BMSBpanel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;BMSB sticky panel 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/Ar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Anastatus reduvii on BMSB egg mass 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Field season 2020 is done, and I’m looking forward to analyzing the data, parasitoid identifications, and preparing to the next summer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Started as an Assistant Research Scientist in Dr. Shrewsbury’s lab!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/08/started-a-new-position/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Started as an Assistant Research Scientist in Dr. Shrewsbury's lab!" /><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/08/started-a-new-position</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/08/started-a-new-position/">&lt;p&gt;I am very excited to join Dr. Paula Shrewsbury’s lab as an Assistant Research Scientist! In my new position, I continue my research on novel species interactions and will focus on native and introduced parasitoid interactions for biocontrol of the invasive brown marmorated stink bug. &lt;!--more--&gt; I’m very happy and looking forward to my new research adventure!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am very excited to join Dr. Paula Shrewsbury’s lab as an Assistant Research Scientist! In my new position, I continue my research on novel species interactions and will focus on native and introduced parasitoid interactions for biocontrol of the invasive brown marmorated stink bug.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Presented at Botany 2020 - Virtual!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/botany-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presented at Botany 2020 - Virtual!" /><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/botany-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/botany-meeting/">&lt;p&gt;This week I presented at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2020.botanyconference.org/&quot;&gt;Botany-2020 virtual meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Annual Meeting of the Botanical Society of America. &lt;!--more--&gt; It was quite a new experience, as I’m sure it was for everyone - video recording, answering questions in chats, etc. I really enjoyed the talks, and I really liked how well all the sections, workshops, etc. were organized. I can only imagine the amount of work which had been done to make it happen in this difficult and stressful time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I presented one of my research projects on novel plant-insect interactions. In this project, we explored variation in plant responses to grasshopper herbivory among the cultivars of the introduced Miscanthus sinensis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a video recording of my talk, and here are my &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2020_Botany_talk.pdf&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gZJb6n5DNWo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week I presented at the Botany-2020 virtual meeting, Annual Meeting of the Botanical Society of America.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Developed an undergraduate course in Invasion Ecology</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/invasion-ecology-course/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developed an undergraduate course in Invasion Ecology" /><published>2020-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/invasion-ecology-course</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/invasion-ecology-course/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve finished developing the main outline of my course in Invasion Ecology which I hope to teach some day. This is a semester-long course; I see it as an upper-division undergraduate course but I think it can be easily adapted for a low-division undergraduate course or an elective graduate course. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invasion ecology is a fascinating area to me: Why do some introduced species become invasive? Why do some introduced species fail to establish? What can we do to learn more about invasive species?, etc. All these questions have been driving my research since my doctoral studies at the University of Cincinnati. This course has been my ‘pet’ project since then, and I developed it based on both my own research and teaching experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve designed this course to include weekly lectures and laboratories, weekly homework, online quizzes, as well as a mid-term and cumulative final exam. During both lectures and laboratories students would design and conduct experiments, develop and present group projects, participate in short local field trips, write article critiques, analyze case studies, and develop risk assessment protocols. I’d like my future students to gain all this experience and see themselves as scientists in training during that semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course outline with examples of lecture slides, assignments and worksheets are available &lt;a href=&quot;http://alinaavanesyan.com/courses/invasion-ecology&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. 
I’m currently exploring online alternatives for experimental laboratories and field trips. I really enjoyed developing this course, and I know I’ll enjoy even more teaching it some day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wD-umL1EGBo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invasive spotted lanternfly, Lycorma delicatula, my current primary research object. We know so little about this unusual and one of the most aggressive forest insect pests in the eastern US. (4th nymphal instar, 7/17/2018, Berks County, PA)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve finished developing the main outline of my course in Invasion Ecology which I hope to teach some day. This is a semester-long course; I see it as an upper-division undergraduate course but I think it can be easily adapted for a low-division undergraduate course or an elective graduate course.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our paper on molecular gut content analysis of the invasive spotted lanternfly published in Insects!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/lanternfly-paper-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our paper on molecular gut content analysis of the invasive spotted lanternfly published in Insects!" /><published>2020-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/lanternfly-paper-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/lanternfly-paper-published/">&lt;p&gt;So happy to see our &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3390/insects11040215&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on molecular gut content analysis of the invasive spotted lanternfly, Lycorma delicatula, published today in Insects special issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mdpi.com/journal/insects/special_issues/gut_trophic_interact&quot;&gt;“Molecular Gut Content Analysis: Deciphering Trophic Interactions of Insects”&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;!--more--&gt; 
This paper summarizes the results of my work on molecular confirmation of diet of the spotted lanternfly. In this study we showed, for the first time, that host plant DNA can be identified within the gut contents of the spotted lanternfly and demonstrated the use of this approach for deciphering the host plant range of the lanternfly. I’m very happy to get it done and be able to share. I’m also very thankful to Darsy, Jessica, and Nurani - my mentees and great helpers - who helped me with routine DNA extraction, sequence editing, and depositing sequences to NCBI GenBank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is our &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2020_SLF_gut_content.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avanesyan, A., and W.O. Lamp. (2020) Use of molecular gut content analysis to decipher the range of food plants of the invasive spotted lanternfly, Lycorma delicatula. Insects: Special Issue “ Molecular Gut Content Analysis: Deciphering Trophic Interactions of Insects”, 11(4), 215, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3390/insects11040215&quot;&gt;doi.org/10.3390/insects11040215&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few selected figures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/fig2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Overview of the main activities of the study: collection L. delicatula nymphs and plant samples, DNA isolation from plant samples and L. delicatula gut contents, identification plant species, and determining lanternfly-plant associations.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/fig3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Average sequence quality scores (QS) and contiguous read length (CRL) of the plant sequences isolated from gut contents of L. delicatula nymphs (SLF) and from the intact plant samples
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/novel_associations/fig4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Results of identification of plant species ingested by L. delicatula nymphs, based on sequences obtained for a portion of the chloroplast rbcL gene
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So happy to see our paper on molecular gut content analysis of the invasive spotted lanternfly, Lycorma delicatula, published today in Insects special issue “Molecular Gut Content Analysis: Deciphering Trophic Interactions of Insects”!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Joined the Reviewer Board for journal ‘Insects’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/joined-reviewer-board/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joined the Reviewer Board for journal 'Insects'" /><published>2020-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/joined-reviewer-board</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/joined-reviewer-board/">&lt;p&gt;I have accepted an invitation to join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mdpi.com/journal/insects/submission_reviewers&quot;&gt;Reviewer Board&lt;/a&gt; for journal “Insects”! I’ll be serving as a reviewer in the following subject areas: molecular gut content analysis, eDNA, DNA barcoding, invasion ecology, plant-insect interactions, insect morphology, and host plant usage. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to continue my longtime collaboration with journal “Insects” as an author, reviewer, guest editor, and now a member of the journal’s Reviewer Board. I’ve been enjoying all of my interactions with the editorial board of this journal and I’m always impressed by its timely responses, reviews, interesting special issues, and a speedy publication process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/Insects.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have accepted an invitation to join the Reviewer Board for journal “Insects”! I’ll be serving as a reviewer in the following subject areas: molecular gut content analysis, eDNA, DNA barcoding, invasion ecology, plant-insect interactions, insect morphology, and host plant usage.</summary></entry></feed>