<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-09T15:10:00-06:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Alina Avanesyan</title><subtitle>Alina's personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Week 5 of Planting Science program</title><link href="/blog/2017/10/planting-science/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 5 of Planting Science program" /><published>2017-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/10/planting-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/10/planting-science/">&lt;p&gt;It has been 5 weeks of Planting Science program and my online mentorship of high school
students teams in their plant investigations.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy it and I can't stop being impressed how well everything is organized: all possible
questions I might have are in weekly newsletters, mentors' online resources, or in group
announcements. And if (if!) I can't find an answer to my question I can always post it on our
forums and will get help right away – literally, within 10-15 min. Amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been mentoring three research teams so far and I am serving as a liaison for a teacher and her
three student teams. Interactions with students are incredibly rewarding, and I feel very lucky to
be involved in this program!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It has been 5 weeks of Planting Science program and my online mentorship of high school students teams in their plant investigations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New (or old?) mode of transport for invasive species</title><link href="/blog/2017/10/invasive-species/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New (or old?) mode of transport for invasive species" /><published>2017-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/10/invasive-species</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/10/invasive-species/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.care2.com/causes/invasive-species-are-still-hitching-rides-on-tsunami-debris.html&quot;&gt;Carlton et al. Science 29 Sep 2017:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”..We document 289 living Japanese coastal marine species from
16 phyla transported over 6 years on objects that traveled thousands of kilometers across the
Pacific Ocean&lt;!--more--&gt; to the shores of North America and Hawai‘i. Most of this dispersal occurred on
nonbiodegradable objects, resulting in the longest documented transoceanic survival and dispersal of
coastal species by rafting…”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I study invasive species the more I realize how little I (we?) know about them: they can
adapt to a new habitat relatively easily, they successfully compete with native species, they
disperse fast, and apparently long distance is also not an obstacle for them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Carlton et al. Science 29 Sep 2017: ”..We document 289 living Japanese coastal marine species from 16 phyla transported over 6 years on objects that traveled thousands of kilometers across the Pacific Ocean</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yet another trip to Colorado</title><link href="/blog/2017/07/another-trip-to-colorado/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yet another trip to Colorado" /><published>2017-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/07/another-trip-to-colorado</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/07/another-trip-to-colorado/">&lt;p&gt;Last week I spent in Colorado Springs at the Digging Deeper Summer Professional Development workshop
which is part of my Planting Science fellowship I received earlier this year. &lt;!--more--&gt; It was
wonderful experience: I enjoyed meeting biology teachers and other scientist mentors, and I’ve
learned a lot.  If you would have asked me “Where does the tree mass come from?” a week ago I would
have hard time explaining this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a wonderful trip to the Garden of the Gods: red rocks are just gorgeous. Every time I
go to Colorado I discover something new. We also went to a “plant walk”, which was a 40 min-walk
from the BSCS building to our hotel accompanied by identification of plants we saw and amazing
stories about them – many thanks to our ‘tour guide’, Catrina!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to start working with teachers and their student teams this Fall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/misc/plantingscience1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
       &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Digging Deeper Summer Professional Development&lt;br /&gt;
    July 23-27, 2017. Colorado Springs, CO.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last week I spent in Colorado Springs at the Digging Deeper Summer Professional Development workshop which is part of my Planting Science fellowship I received earlier this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our GenBank submission has just been approved!</title><link href="/blog/2017/05/genbank/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our GenBank submission has just been approved!" /><published>2017-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/05/genbank</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/05/genbank/">&lt;p&gt;Our GenBank submission has just been approved! Here it is:&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backer, S., Christiansen, K., Christofferson, D., Geisinger, S., Graving, S., Jones, K., Miller, R.,
Omanovic, E., Piatt, D., Reyes-Zuniga, K., Salazar-Klock, L., Sopher, K., Welsch, A., Avanesyan, A.,
and I. Hazan. (2017) Salvia rosmarinus isolate rs GAPC-2 gene, partial cds. Direct Submission,
GenBank Accession no. MF074139&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to my students who did a great job choosing a plant species (in the first place!) for
which a partial sequence for the GAPDH gene (GAPC-2, 1139 bp) previously hasn’t been described, and
who, of course, worked hard on isolating and cloning this part of the gene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/courses/molecular-biology/&quot;&gt;More details about this project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our GenBank submission has just been approved! Here it is:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three poster presentations of my students. Great job, guys!</title><link href="/blog/2017/04/student-posters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three poster presentations of my students. Great job, guys!" /><published>2017-04-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-04-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/04/student-posters</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/04/student-posters/">&lt;p&gt;Today my students presented their molecular biology term projects at 4th Annual Grand View
Scholarship Symposium. Very exciting! &lt;!--more--&gt;We were very nervous at the beginning of the semester when we
started cloning the GAPDH gene from cilantro and rosemary (my students’ plant choice!) It was a very
challenging project: sometime a time period of a lab was simply not enough to finish PCR or check
bacterial growth. Students did a good job coming to the lab after or between classes to take care of
their samples. Many thanks to our lab administrator, Jennifer Donnelly, and the department head,
Idit Hazan, for their help with preparing samples and taking care of plants, as well as all the
supplies we needed during the semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything could have gone wrong at any time, but here we go, we have three beautiful posters and 13
happy students who are proud of their work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Omanovic E., Welsch A., Graving S., Christiansen K., Avanesyan A., Hazan I. Sequencing of GAPDH Gene
in Cilantro and Rosemary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christofferson D., Miller R., Piatt D., Backer S., Reyes-Zuniga K., Avanesyan A., Hazan I.
Sequencing the GAPDH Gene of Rosmarinus officinalis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geisinger S., Jones K., Sopher K., Salazar-Klock L., Avanesyan A., Hazan I. Sequencing of GAPDH Gene
in Coriandrum sativum (Cilantro).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, sequence of the GAPDH gene from rosemary, turned out to be particularly good, and we
are currently preparing it for submission to NCBI GenBank. Feels great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row mt-4 mb-4&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;figure mb-0&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2017_studentposter1.pdf&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-thumb figure-img img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2017_studentposter1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-left&quot;&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Student authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Omanovic E., Welsch A., Graving S., Christiansen K.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;figure mb-0&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2017_studentposter2.pdf&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-thumb figure-img img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2017_studentposter2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-left&quot;&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Student authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Christofferson D., Miller R., Piatt D., Backer S., Reyes-Zuniga K.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;figure mb-0&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2017_studentposter3.pdf&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-thumb figure-img img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2017_studentposter3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-left&quot;&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Student authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Geisinger S., Jones K., Sopher K., Salazar-Klock L.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid w-40&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/courses/molecularbiology/gv_symposium.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Annual Grand View Scholarship Symposium. Poster presentations&lt;br /&gt; Des Moines, IA; April 21, 2017.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today my students presented their molecular biology term projects at 4th Annual Grand View Scholarship Symposium. Very exciting!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paper published in Insects!</title><link href="/blog/2017/03/paper-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper published in Insects!" /><published>2017-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/03/paper-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/03/paper-published/">&lt;p&gt;My paper from my &lt;a href=&quot;/research/drosophila-suzukii-raspberry/&quot;&gt;postdoctoral work&lt;/a&gt; has been just published in Insects, in special issue “Invasive
insect species&lt;!--more--&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avanesyan, A., Jaffe, B.D., and C. Guédot (2017) Isolating spermatheca and determining mating status
of the invasive spotted wing drosophila, Drosophila suzukii: a protocol for tissue dissection and
its applications. Insects: Special issue “Invasive Insect Species”. 8(1), 32;
doi:10.3390/insects8010032. Invited paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper describes a step-by-step protocol for tissue dissection, isolating spermathecae, and
determining the mating status of females which I developed specifically for invasive Drosophila
suzukii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Claire Mattmiller, a high school student whom I mentored, for numerous fly
dissections she made and several illustrations which have been included in this manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;figure mb-0&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&quot;figure-img img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/drosophila/spermateca1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-left&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&quot;figure-img img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/projects/drosophila/spermateca2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption text-left&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My paper from my postdoctoral work has been just published in Insects, in special issue “Invasive insect species</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My last dissertation chapter is published! Now I can retire…</title><link href="/blog/2016/12/last-chapter-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My last dissertation chapter is published! Now I can retire..." /><published>2016-12-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2016-12-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/12/last-chapter-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/12/last-chapter-published/">&lt;p&gt;It will be included in January issue of The Journal of the Torrey Botanical Society:&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avanesyan, A., and T.M. Culley (2017) Tolerance of native and exotic prairie grasses to herbivory by
Melanoplus grasshoppers: application of a non-destructive method for estimating plant biomass
changes as a response to herbivory. The Journal of the Torrey Botanical Society 144(1):15-25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was one of my last experiments on plant responses to grasshopper herbivory which I conducted in
Ohio and Maryland. In this study we wanted to estimate changes in plant biomass (a proxy for plant
tolerance) without clipping the plants. Interestingly, we’ve found that for the most grasses we used
the predictor variable [plant height x number of leaves] was the best. Most likely it works for
grasses only, but I am curious to see what combination of measurements would work for other plants.
Maybe I will test it in some future experiments..&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It will be included in January issue of The Journal of the Torrey Botanical Society:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Started working at Grand View University</title><link href="/blog/2016/08/started-at-grand-view/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Started working at Grand View University" /><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/08/started-at-grand-view</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/08/started-at-grand-view/">&lt;p&gt;I am very excited to join Department of Biology at Grand View University in Des Moines, IA as an
adjunct Genetics Instructor!&lt;!--more--&gt; I’ll be teaching two sections of an upper-level Genetics
laboratory course for biotechnology majors this Fall, and (hopefully!) Molecular Biology lab in the
Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The university is quite a commute (2 hours from my home, oh well..), but I am really excited about
teaching genetics – one of my favorite courses and research areas. The lab equipment and supplies
are really impressive, small classes, cozy buildings, friendly faculty – I’m very much looking
forward to starting my semester!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid w-50&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/gvu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grand View University&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Grand View University, Des Moines, IA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am very excited to join Department of Biology at Grand View University in Des Moines, IA as an adjunct Genetics Instructor!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">More Media Coverage</title><link href="/blog/2014/03/more-media-coverage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More Media Coverage" /><published>2014-03-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2014-03-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2014/03/more-media-coverage</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2014/03/more-media-coverage/">&lt;p&gt;Another story about my research on plant DNA detection from grasshopper gut contents has been just
published in India!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.downtoearth.org.in/content/gut-instinct&quot;&gt;“Gut Instinct”&lt;/a&gt;.
This is a science magazine, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.downtoearth.org.in/&quot;&gt;Down to Earth&lt;/a&gt;, published by
the Society for Environmental Communications, India.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Another story about my research on plant DNA detection from grasshopper gut contents has been just published in India!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Another paper published!</title><link href="/blog/2014/02/paper-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Another paper published!" /><published>2014-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2014-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2014/02/paper-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2014/02/paper-published/">&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2014_dna.pdf&quot;&gt;protocol paper&lt;/a&gt; just came out in the February
issue of Applications in Plant Sciences!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The press release for this paper is &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2014_dna_pressrelease.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper was also featured in several places such as 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2014/02/140205143758.htm&quot;&gt;ScienceDaily&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencenewsline.com/articles/2014020523520003.html&quot;&gt;ScienceNewsLine&lt;/a&gt;, and 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bio-medicine.org/biology-news-1/Grasshoppers-are-what-they-eat-33959-1/&quot;&gt;Bio-Medicine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My protocol paper just came out in the February issue of Applications in Plant Sciences!</summary></entry></feed>