<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-03T22:44:24-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Alina Avanesyan</title><subtitle>Alina's personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Presented at the MOFFA meeting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/moffa-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presented at the MOFFA meeting" /><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/moffa-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/moffa-meeting/">&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday I presented at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://marylandorganic.org/events/&quot;&gt;Annual Meeting of the Maryland Organic Food &amp;amp; Farming Association&lt;/a&gt; (Maryland Dept. of Agriculture, Annapolis, MD). &lt;!--more--&gt; It was a very interesting experience: it was my first formal talk on the spotted lanternfly and its host usage. The spotted lanternfly has not officially invaded Maryland yet (and we hope it will not - only one male individual has been found so far), but it was very important to share all we know about the lanternfly life cycle and behavior with our farmers and growers.  Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2019_moffa.pdf&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last Saturday I presented at the Annual Meeting of the Maryland Organic Food &amp;amp; Farming Association (Maryland Dept. of Agriculture, Annapolis, MD).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sophonia paper published!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/01/sophonia-paper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sophonia paper published!" /><published>2019-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/01/sophonia-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/01/sophonia-paper/">&lt;p&gt;This paper is on interactions of exotic leafhopper, &lt;i&gt;Sophonia orientalis&lt;/i&gt;, with its novel hosts in Hawaii. It took quite a bit to analyze two-year data, to write a manuscript, and to wait for all of the reviewers’ comments. &lt;!--more--&gt; But now it is published in Environmental Entomology! Here is our &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2019_sophonia.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;, and here are we in our departmental &lt;a href=&quot;https://entomology.umd.edu/news/umd-researchers-study-plant-responses-to-leafhopper-injury&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt;. Feels great!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This paper is on interactions of exotic leafhopper, Sophonia orientalis, with its novel hosts in Hawaii. It took quite a bit to analyze two-year data, to write a manuscript, and to wait for all of the reviewers’ comments.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My departmental seminar talk</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/11/seminar-talk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My departmental seminar talk" /><published>2018-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/11/seminar-talk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/11/seminar-talk/">&lt;p&gt;I gave my first talk at our weekly departmental seminar: “Novel plant-insect associations: implication of the lack of coevolution”. It was very exciting and interesting experience, &lt;!--more--&gt; and I got many interesting ideas from the audience on my future research directions. 
My talk is &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2018_seminar_talk.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Also, my labmates wrote a very cool &lt;a href=&quot;https://entomology.umd.edu/news/protect-or-destroy-the-role-of-native-grasshoppers-in-their-home-habitats&quot;&gt;seminar blog&lt;/a&gt; on my talk.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I gave my first talk at our weekly departmental seminar: “Novel plant-insect associations: implication of the lack of coevolution”. It was very exciting and interesting experience,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Busy 2018 ESA meeting in Vancouver!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/11/esa-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Busy 2018 ESA meeting in Vancouver!" /><published>2018-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/11/esa-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/11/esa-meeting/">&lt;p&gt;This time the ESA meeting (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entsoc.org/event-calendar/2018-esa-esc-and-esbc-joint-annual-meeting-entomology-2018&quot;&gt;2018 ESA, ESC, and ESBC Joint Annual Meeting&lt;/a&gt;) was especially busy for me. I served as a moderator in one session, a judge in two other sessions; &lt;!--more--&gt; I was responsible for setting up our UMD booth in the Exhibit Hall; I also gave a talk and presented a poster – whew! I spent a wonderful time listening various talks, discussing our work on the spotted lanternfly with our colleagues from Penn State University, and of course, enjoying beautiful Vancouver!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This time the ESA meeting (2018 ESA, ESC, and ESBC Joint Annual Meeting) was especially busy for me. I served as a moderator in one session, a judge in two other sessions;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review paper published!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/review-paper-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review paper published!" /><published>2018-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/review-paper-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/review-paper-published/">&lt;p&gt;My systematic review and meta-analysis on feeding preferences of acridid grasshoppers on native vs.
introduced plants has just been published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mdpi.com/2223-7747/7/4/83&quot;&gt;Plants, Special Issue “Plants Interacting with other
Organisms: Insects”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;!--more--&gt; It has been quite a long and challenging process with 3 rounds of
revision and incorporating comments from 5(!) reviewers, but I’m really excited to see it published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/grasshopper-iowa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;Differential grasshopper, Melanoplus differentials (Orthoptera:
  Acrididae), eating our palm tree on our balcony, on the 3rd floor. 
  &lt;br /&gt;Photo credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ic4f.me&quot;&gt;Sergey&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This systematic review entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/content/publications/2018_should_i_eat.pdf&quot;&gt;Should I eat or should I go? Acridid grasshoppers and their novel
host plants: potential for biotic resistance&lt;/a&gt;” 
aimed to identify patterns of grasshopper feeding preferences for native versus introduced plants
and, consequently, a potential of grasshoppers to provide biotic resistance of native communities.
I’ve worked on this review for a total of almost 2 years: I collected 2146 studies (from six
databases) published during 1967–2017. Only 13 studies satisfied all of my inclusion criteria; from
these, I was able to extract 63 records of feeding preference trials for 28 North-American
grasshopper species. These trials involved direct comparison between consumed native and introduced
plant material, and these records were included in the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to present a poster on this paper at the upcoming ESA meeting in Vancouver, CA. So I
discussed with my PI the best way of presenting it since it is virtually impossible to fit all the
details and analysis in one poster. His advice was very simple: to present the main message I’d like
to tell people and support it with evidence. I was thinking about this one message, and I came up
with five(!) things which were the most surprising for me and which I definitely would want to
share:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acridid grasshoppers prefer to feed on introduced plants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of these plants are highly invasive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grasshoppers prefer to feed on them regardless the experimental conditions (greenhouse, field,
etc.) or plant material offered (clipped leaves, stems, plants in pots, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The authors use a very wide range of measurements. From 63 records I counted 35 different
measurements the authors used to assess grasshopper preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of these measurements were not standardized. Only 12 out of 35 measurements were
standardized in some way (by time or grasshopper weight).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I collected these data and wrote the main parts of these manuscript while we lived in Iowa.  So the
graphical abstract (see above) is special for me: it is a shot of a grasshopper eating our palm tree
on our balcony in Iowa, on the 3rd floor!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My systematic review and meta-analysis on feeding preferences of acridid grasshoppers on native vs. introduced plants has just been published in Plants, Special Issue “Plants Interacting with other Organisms: Insects”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer News!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/summer-news/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer News!" /><published>2018-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/summer-news</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/summer-news/">&lt;p&gt;Summer is over. It was a busy Summer - full of interesting work, trips, and a lot of writing.
Looking back, I’m happy to share a few highlights.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;subject-editor-for-the-journal-of-orthoptera-research&quot;&gt;Subject Editor for the Journal of Orthoptera Research!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I’ve been offered to serve as a Subject Editor for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jor.pensoft.net/browse_journal_groups.php?role_id=3&amp;amp;journal_name=jor&quot;&gt;Journal of Orthoptera
Research&lt;/a&gt;. It was super exciting! I served as a reviewer for this journal before for about 2 years,
and I really enjoyed it. I also constantly refer to this journal in my research since it is the only
journal we have so far where you can find everything about grasshoppers in one place!  My editing
work is in a full mode now - I’ve been editing the manuscripts in the areas of Biodiversity &amp;amp;
Conservation, General Ecology, and Molecular Biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also very happy to be featured in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/5b6be1cff4e3/department-of-entomology-newslettersummer-2018?e=d62b3d56d4&quot;&gt;departmental
newsletter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;planning-umd-postdoctoral-research-symposium&quot;&gt;Planning UMD Postdoctoral Research Symposium..&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the past summer, I served on the planning committee for the first (ever!) &lt;a href=&quot;https://gradschool.umd.edu/postdocs/career-and-professional-development/postdoctoral-research-symposium&quot;&gt;UMD Postdoctoral
Research
Symposium&lt;/a&gt;. The symposium is almost here (on Sep 17), we’ve planned several interesting
workshops (getting grants, designing a new course, etc.) - should be fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-to-plantingscience&quot;&gt;Back to PlantingScience!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very happy to be back to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://alinaavanesyan.com/planting-science/&quot;&gt;PlantingScience program&lt;/a&gt;, this time as a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plantingscience.org/groups/mpst&quot;&gt;Master Plant
Science Team&lt;/a&gt;! I will serve as a liaison for one class of high school students and as a scientist
mentor for 2-3 teams. I had incredibly rewarding experience participating in the Digging Deeper
project last year and I’ve decided to stay with PlantingScience forever!  I’m very much looking
forward to continuing my work with teachers and students this academic year and together with them
enjoy science!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;maes-proposal-funded&quot;&gt;MAES proposal funded!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least was that one of our two lanternfly proposals has been funded by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://agresearch.umd.edu/&quot;&gt;The Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station&lt;/a&gt;, McIntire Stennis Forestry Research Program. These news
came as a wonderful surprise on Friday, Aug 31 late afternoon (the last possible day for such
notifications) with the starting date Sep 1. This is super exciting, my work on the spotted
lanternfly began a few months ago, now we have some preserved specimens, and I don’t have to wait
anymore to ‘officially’ start exploring them. More details to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/grasshopper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Summer is over. It was a busy Summer - full of interesting work, trips, and a lot of writing. Looking back, I’m happy to share a few highlights.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maryland Day in pictures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/maryland-day-in-pictures/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maryland Day in pictures" /><published>2018-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/maryland-day-in-pictures</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/maryland-day-in-pictures/">&lt;p&gt;We spent a wonderful time on campus celebrating our annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://marylandday.umd.edu/&quot;&gt;Maryland Day&lt;/a&gt;! I was really impressed how
well everything was organized and how many things there were to do with friends and family, and of
course with little and not so little kids. &lt;!--more--&gt;We came there for 2 hours and stayed for the whole day!
My daughter enjoyed our insect petting zoo very much, although she refused to touch the tarantula
(well, I don’t blame her); but “scooping bugs” was by far her favorite thing to do. She also was
fascinated with all the insect models and stickers with insects; and of course she immediately
“borrowed” the toy-grasshopper from my office desk once she had spotted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried some other things, too: we got to the barn where we touched sheep and watched beautiful
horses. Ice-cream, a balloon, a police cap, lots of candies, and wonderful weather were included!
This was the first time I took my daughter to my work - she said she liked it very much, and I’m
pretty sure she thinks now that my work is Maryland Day every day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    My first time decorating the entrance
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    Insect petting zoo. Getting ready!  
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    Bugs are fascinating!
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    First collection 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    Getting wet with my labmates  
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    Stickers - the best award!
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    Finally could touch something.. 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
     &quot;Mommy, I don’t want it on my hand&quot; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    DNA chain, our contribution is the last yellow piece
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    Enjoying candies and nice weather 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    Second favorite stop after Insect Zoo
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4 col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/md-day-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    So much fun!
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We spent a wonderful time on campus celebrating our annual Maryland Day! I was really impressed how well everything was organized and how many things there were to do with friends and family, and of course with little and not so little kids.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My first adventures in the aquatic world</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/first-adventures-aquatic-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first adventures in the aquatic world" /><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/first-adventures-aquatic-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/first-adventures-aquatic-world/">&lt;p&gt;Being almost exclusively ‘terrestrial’ person in my research it has been quite an interesting
experience for me to “get wet” with both Dr. Lamp’s lab and his Aquatic Entomology class. &lt;!--more--&gt;
Although I am a TA in this class I fully participate in all the student activities. It’s fun, but
also I can’t stop being surprised of how different things are under water. Well, here are my first
impression:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first surprise for me was the fact that apparently there is no such thing as “traditional”
plant-insect interactions in aquatic communities. Everyone (all insects) eats almost everything (all
leaves which fall in a stream), and all “tastes” the same as long as it provides enough nutrients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also didn’t know that it is not a leaf itself that attracts aquatic insects, but a biofilm - a
bunch of different microorganisms which stick to each other and to a surface of a leaf. I learned
that “the leaf with such biofilm for aquatic insects is like a toast with peanut butter for us: a
toast itself is edible of course, but with peanut butter it is a completely different food”
(borrowed from Becca W.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are some pictures from my first collections and insect identifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/aquatic2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/aquatic3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/aquatic4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/aquatic5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Being almost exclusively ‘terrestrial’ person in my research it has been quite an interesting experience for me to “get wet” with both Dr. Lamp’s lab and his Aquatic Entomology class.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring family-friendly places in Maryland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/exploring-family-friendly-maryland/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring family-friendly places in Maryland" /><published>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/exploring-family-friendly-maryland</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/exploring-family-friendly-maryland/">&lt;p&gt;If not every weekend, but at least every other weekend we try to get out to a new place with our
growing little one. &lt;!--more--&gt; I was glad to find out that here in Maryland we could find plenty of
such opportunities within an hour-drive from home, and often less than that.  Here are the places we
have visited so far. Our daughter was super excited about each of them and if she could she would go
to each of them every day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;maryland-heights&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/hafe/learn/historyculture/maryland-heights.htm&quot;&gt;Maryland Heights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feb, 2018 – it was cold, windy, and rainy, but we made it! We’ve picked a nice kids-friendly trail
with a gorgeous view on the Potomac River.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-8&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;roers-zoofari&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.roerszoofari.com&quot;&gt;Roer’s Zoofari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March, 2018 – it is a nice open air zoo with 20-min safari bus ride. We fed goats and llamas,
enjoyed birds, giraffes, camels, cheetahs, and tried not to wake kangaroos up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-7&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-left&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-7&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-original-playhouse-childrens-museum&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://originalplayhouse.com&quot;&gt;The Original Playhouse Childrens Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April, 2018 – this is exclusively for kids, of course. It has several themed rooms – our daughter
enjoyed playing with water, construction tools, blocks, pretend snakes in the pretend rainforest,
and even a little theatre. Finally we all enjoyed playing outside on a very original playground with
a castle and a hidden slide which for some reason reminded me of the slopes in Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cunningham-falls-state-park&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dnr.maryland.gov/publiclands/Pages/western/cunningham.aspx&quot;&gt;Cunningham Falls State Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April, 2018 – we apparently went not to the best trail for kids, but according to what I’ve read the
park has a lot of different trails with beautiful views. So we are looking forward to exploring it
more. Nevertheless, the weather was beautiful, and we were glad to spend a couple of hours hiking
and exploring all the sticks and pine cones our daughter could find (extremely hard task). I was
also on watch out for the spotted lanternfly, but nothing so far. Not yet, I guess..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;ic4f-mtrig ic4f-zoomin figure-img img-fluid ic4f-max-height-md&quot; src=&quot;/assets/content/blog/exploring-md-13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;figure-caption&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If not every weekend, but at least every other weekend we try to get out to a new place with our growing little one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting a postdoc at the University of Maryland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/postdoc-umd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting a postdoc at the University of Maryland" /><published>2018-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/postdoc-umd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/postdoc-umd/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve just started as a Postdoctoral Associate at the Department of Entomology at the University of
Maryland! &lt;!--more--&gt;This job offer came to me as a wonderful Christmas present, and we packed and moved to
Maryland within 2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clfs.umd.edu/entm/lamp/index.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Bill Lamp’s lab&lt;/a&gt;,
where I will continue my research on ecology and evolution of plant-insect interactions. My primary
focus will be novel associations between native and introduced species and their effect on natural
and managed systems. Dr. Lamp has been my mentor for a long time, and we’ve been collaborating on
several projects since my doctoral studies in Cincinnati. So working in his lab as a postdoc is a
great opportunity for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited about my new position, we love our new place in Maryland, and I am looking forward
to my next couple of years in the Lamp lab!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve just started as a Postdoctoral Associate at the Department of Entomology at the University of Maryland!</summary></entry></feed>